A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The Engineering Education Program at Universidad del Valle, Cali, Colombia (Reports 000321), 1963; Corson, Dale R.; Spencer, James W. (James Wendell); Fehr, Robert O. (Box 17)
  Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Colombia; Universidad del Valle
- Ford Foundation mission to Colombia (Reports 000322), 1960; Morse, Richard M. (Richard McGee), 1922-2001; Wolf, Alfred C.; Wickham, Robert S. (Box 18)
  Following a socioeconomic overview of Colombia, the three areas of Foundation support are discussed: 1) higher education 2) rural development 3) public administration improvement.
  Universities and colleges -- Colombia; Human geography -- Colombia; Economics -- Colombia; Politics, Practical -- Colombia; Human capital -- Colombia; Education, Higher -- Colombia; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Colombia; Rural development
- Political and economic profile of Colombia: Ford Foundation mission to Colombia (Reports 000323), 1960; Morse, Richard M. (Richard McGee), 1922-2001; Wickham, Robert S.; Wolf, Alfred C. (Box 18)
  21 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Political parties -- Research -- Colombia; Political leadership -- Research -- Colombia; Communism -- Colombia; Economics -- Research -- Colombia
- Report on the Trade School Program, Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria, Valparaiso Chile (Reports 000325), 1965; Peters, Donald F. (Box 18)
  A report of progress of technical assistance for the development of the Trade School Program of the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria, Valparaiso Chile: June 1964-June 1965
  Overseas Division/Latin America;Latin America and the Caribbean/Argentia and the Southern Cone
  06400299
  The William Hood Dunwoody Industrial Institute
  60 p.
  Progress report;no. 1
  Technical education -- Chile; Manual training -- Chile; Vocational education -- Chile; Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María; William Hood Dunwoody Industrial Institute
- Mexico Agricultural Program (Reports 000326), 1963; Gamble, William K., 1920- (Box 18)
  Agricultural extension is studied to project needs for Ford Foundation support.
  06390489;06590048
  Rural extension -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Mexico -- Economic aspects; State of Mexico. Agricultural Extension Service (Mexico)
- Spaeth/Howard report on Latin American studies (Reports 000327), 1964; Spaeth, Carl Bernhardt, 1907-; Howard, John Brooks (Box 18, Reel R-9301)
  Three questions are researched 1)how can Latin American studies in the United States be improved through American students and teachers visiting Latin America 2)what obstacles would political climate present to such cooperation 3)what is the political con
  University cooperation -- Latin America; Teacher exchange programs -- Latin America; Student exchange programs -- Latin America
- Visit to Mexico and South America, July 8-September 5, 1961 (Reports 000328), Katz, Milton (Box 18)
  Legal education and the law are discussed.
  Law schools -- Latin America; Law -- Latin America; Law -- Study and teaching -- Latin America; Lawyers -- Latin America
- Report of a visit to Mexico and South America: July 8-September 5, 1961: journal notes (Reports 000329), Katz, Milton (Box 18)
  Legal education and its relation to the entire socioeconomic-political spectrum is the subject here.
  International Affairs
  135 p.
  Lawyers -- Latin America; Law schools -- Latin America; Law -- Study and teaching -- Latin America
- Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria (Reports 000330), 1963; Butler, John A.; Haxby, Bernard V.; Verbrugge, Frank, 1913- (Box 18)
  Includes appendices a, b, c, and d under separate cover. The university is surveyed with a view of laying the groundwork for a general development plan for the university over a period of ten or more years.
  142 p.
  Curriculum evaluation -- Chile; Vocational education -- Chile; Manual training -- Chile; Technical education -- Chile; Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María
- Research undertakings that may be submitted to the Division of Population Studies of the Colombian Association of Medical Faculties during 1965 (Reports 000331), 1964; Saunders, Lyle (Box 18, Reel R-9301)
  University programs in demography and population education are surveyed.
  Birth control -- Colombia; Human reproduction -- Research -- Colombia; Population -- Research; Demography -- Colombia; Colombian Association of Faculties of Medicine.
- Preliminary investigation of the libraries of the University of Chile (Reports 000332), 1965; Miles, Paul M. (Box 18)
  Entire report in Spanish. A partial English translation, Preliminary investigation of the libraries of the University of Chile, appears within this folder under under separate cover. A study was made of all the libraries of the University of Chile.
  06590017;06500327
  157 p.
  Preliminary investigation of the libraries of the University of Chile;Investigacion preliminar de las bibliotecas de la Universidad de Chile
  Academic libraries -- Chile; Libraries -- Chile; Library cooperation -- Chile; Universidad de Chile
- Chilean community facilities program architectural research: First five projects (Reports 000333), 1964; Thomsen, Charles B.; Reed, Bob, 1947-; Anderson, Todd, 1976-; Lacy, Bill; Rice University (Box 18)
  An architectural plan is presented for community facilities which will provide schools, offices, stores, the whole range of community facilities. These centers will act as hubs for each housing development.
  129 p.
  Rural development -- Chile; Community development -- Chile; Architecture -- Research -- Chile; Architecture -- Chile; Rice University
- Education and the making of modern nations (Reports 000334), 1962; Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier) (Box 18)
  Prepared for conference on education and political development, Lake Arrowhead, June 25-29, 1962. Some of the relationships between Western-type education and political development in the contemporary non-Western world, in particular, Africa, are traced.
  Political socialization -- Developing countries; Education -- Developing countries; Political socialization -- Africa; Education -- Africa
- Fitness for self-government and development in Modern Africa (Reports 000335), 1962; Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier) (Box 18)
  Prepared for Fifth World Congress of Sociology, Washington, D.C. September 1962. Title sufficient as abstract.
  World Congress of Sociology (5th: 1962: Washington, D.C.)
  Leadership; Social planning -- Africa; Nationalism -- Africa
- High-level manpower requirements and resources in Tanganyika (Reports 000336), 1963; Tobias, George, 1912- (Box 19)
  06290228
  iv, 65 p.
  Government paper;no. 2
  Human capital -- Tanzania; Occupational training -- Tanzania; Occupational surveys -- Tanzania; Executives -- Training of -- Tanzania
- Working notes covering a proposal for the establishment of an experimental training center in Uganda (Reports 000337), 1961; Thomas, Robert L., 1928- (Box 19, Reel R-9301)
  Following a review of the different occupational categories with which the center would deal, working notes for the operation of the center are given.
  Occupational training -- Uganda; Uganda Electricity Board
- Utilization of manpower in the Kenya Public Service (Reports 000338), 1963; Thurston, John L. (Box 19, Reel R-9301)
  The manpower shortage caused by the departure of expatriates from the civil service is discussed.
  Personnel management -- Kenya; Civil service -- Kenya; Nationalism -- Kenya
- The National Library of Nigeria: a report with recommendations to aid in its establishment (Reports 000339), 1962; White, Carl Milton, 1903-1983 (Box 19)
  Plans for Nigerian legislation to implement the establishment of a national library are given. For related published document, see Reports 004466.
  Africa and the Middle East/West Africa;Office of the Vice President
  06190066
  Library science -- Nigeria; National libraries -- Nigeria; Library planning -- Nigeria; National Library of Nigeria
- Review of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology: Fellows in Africa Program (Reports 000340), 1963; Wilson, Carroll L. (Box 19)
  The purpose of the program is to aid selected African governments by recruiting to their service exceptionally able young Americans whose education is directly relevant to the problems facing these governments.
  Africa and the Middle East;Office of the Vice President
  06000225
  Massachusetts Institute of Technology
  Review of the M.I.T. Fellows in Africa Program
  Civil service -- Africa; Public administration -- Africa; Personnel management -- Africa; Internship programs -- Africa; M.I.T. Fellows in Africa
- Space utilization at the University College, Nairobi, Kenya, March 1966. (Reports 000341), Wood, Frederic C., 1903-; Wood and Tower. (Box 19)
  A statistical study of university facility needs is made.
  Africa and the Middle East/Eastern & Southern Africa;Office of the Vice President
  06490420
  Classroom utilization -- Kenya; School facilities -- Kenya; University of Nairobi
- The ABC Institute: The report of the ABC Committee 1965 Mombasa Mathematics Workshop, Mombasa, Kenya (Reports 000342), Dubisch, Roy, 1917-; Johnson, Paul; Mwizambwe, Gaspar; Williams, Grace Alele; Mombasa Mathematics Workshop; Mombasa Mathematics Workshop (1965: Mombasa, Kenya) (Box 19)
  A proposal is made to hold teacher training institutes to which senior mathematical tutors of the leading training colleges and primary mathematics supervisors from ten English speaking African countries would be invited.
  06200106
  Education Development Center, Inc.
  Mombasa Mathematics Workshop (1965: Mombasa, Kenya)
  Teachers -- Training of -- Kenya; Mathematics teachers -- Kenya; Research institutes -- Kenya; Mathematics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Kenya; Mombasa Mathematics Workshop. ABC Committee.
- Report of survey and evaluation of technical education in Ghana (Reports 000343), 1962; Adams, H. P. (Henry Packwood); Segaar, Arend (Box 19)
  Vocational education is discussed in relation to industrial development.
  Office of the Vice President
  06090093
  81 p.
  Technical education -- Ghana; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Ghana; Vocational education -- Ghana
- The Program of Comparative Fertility Surveys being conducted by the Latin American Demographic Center (Reports 000344), 1966; Miró, Carmen A. (Box 19)
  Fertility, Human -- Latin America; Demography -- Latin America
- Report of a survey of office education needs in Ghana (Reports 000345), 1962; Agnew, Peter Lawrence, 1901-; Atkinson, Phillip S. (Box 19, Reel R-9301)
  Included are papers by James Appiah and T.B.G.S. Addo. Title sufficient as abstract.
  Office education needs in Ghana
  Business education -- Ghana; Business teachers -- Ghana; Occupational surveys -- Ghana
- Papers on industry in Lebanon (Reports 000346), 1964; Calderwood, James D. (Box 19)
  Industrial development and the economics of industrial development are surveyed.
  06390274
  131 p.
  Industrialization -- Lebanon; Industries -- Lebanon; Economics -- Lebanon
- What practicing professionals want from the University of Lagos Evening School of Business (Reports 000347), 1962; Butler, George P. (Box 19)
  A three part program is presented of evening courses to be given to practicing business managers and public administrators. Small business management, and management are some of the curriculum considered.
  06190381
  What practicing business managers and public administrators want the University of Lagos Evening School of Business and Public Administration to offer
  Evening and continuation schools -- Nigeria; Business administration -- Study and teaching; Adult education -- Nigeria; University of Lagos
- Some thoughts and suggestions concerning industrial education and training programs for Saudi Arabia (Reports 000348), 1964; Butler, John A. (Box 19, Reel R-9301)
  Includes paper by Roy Colbert and Clark C. Bloom. Title sufficient as abstract. Accompanied by envelope with brochures and booklets regarding vocational training in Minneapolis.
  Manual training -- Saudi Arabia; Vocational education -- Saudi Arabia
- Vocational agricultural education in developing countries: general remarks and the program in the Syrian Arab Republic (Reports 000350), 1962; Brucher, Felix J. (Box 19)
  Africa and the Middle East/Middle East and North Africa;Office of the Vice President
  06090133
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Syria; Vocational education -- Syria
- Intermediate level agricultural education: objectives, types, and administration (Reports 000351), 1963; Brucher, Felix J.; Near East Meeting on Agricultural Education (1st: 1963: Beirut, Lebanon) (Box 19)
  Agricultural occupation and education in the Middle East are discussed.
  Near East Meeting on Agricultural Education (1st: 1963: Beirut, Lebanon)
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Middle East; Vocational education -- Middle East
- English language teaching in Nigeria: An assessment of the situation with recommendations for action (Reports 000353), 1966; Bamgboṣe, Ayọ (Box 20)
  Survey of all levels of English language teaching in Nigeria. Also included in file is the supplement to the survey team report, dated Dec. 1966 (154 p.).
  195 p.
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria
- Papers on economic planning: Iraq (Reports 000354), 1964; Calderwood, James D.; Paulsen, Arnold (Box 20)
  Planning development is discussed.
  L64-560
  Planning -- Iraq; Iraq. Majlis al-Takhṭīṭ
- Preliminary survey of the Cross River Drainage Basin of Eastern Nigeria (Reports 000355), 1963; Christiansen, James E.; Jones, Francis Clifford; Scrivner, C. L.; Olive, F. R. (Box 20)
  Improvement of the Cross River Drainage Basin through agricultural development is investigated.
  Office of the Vice President; Africa and the Middle East/Middle East and North Africa
  71 p.
  Watersheds -- Nigeria; Agricultural development projects -- Nigeria; Physical geography -- Nigeria; Rural development -- Nigeria
- End of tour report: Intensive Agricultural District Program (Reports 000356), 1965; Miles, Harold A., 1906-1989 (Box 20)
  The benefits of agricultural credit and the increased food production as a result of the intensive agricultural district program are discussed.
  Office of the Vice President;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  56 p.
  Agricultural credit -- India; Rural development -- India; Agriculture -- India -- Economic aspects; Rice -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; India. Intensive Agricultural District Programme
- Recommendations for the establishment of a Faculty of Science at the University of Aleppo, Syria (Reports 000357), 1964; Fisher, Harvey I.; Lauchner, Julian H. (Box 20)
  The establishment of a Faculty of Science at the University of Aleppo, Syria is discussed.
  Overseas Division/Middle East and Africa
  Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Syria
- Program for accelerating private foreign investment in the less developed countries (Reports 000358), 1966; Fleming, Robert I. (Box 20)
  Free enterprise -- Developing countries; Investments -- Developing countries; Economic development
- Review of Ford Foundation program in Israel and Turkey (Reports 000359), 1961; Ginsburg, Benson E. (Box 20)
  05890153
  Research -- Israel; Research -- Turkey; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Israel; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Turkey; Education -- Israel; Education -- Turkey; Subsidies -- Israel; Subsidies -- Turkey
- Report on the College of Agriculture, Pahlavi University (Reports 000360), 1963; Golesorkhi, Nasser (Box 20)
  The operations and program of the agricultural college are studies with reference to possible foundation support for these programs.
  06290465
  College of Agriculture, Pahlavi University
  Agricultural colleges -- Iran; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Iran; School facilities -- Iran; Vocational education -- Iran; Curriculum evaluation -- Iran; Dānishgāh-i Shīrāz; Danishgah-i Pahlavi. College of Agriculture.
- Handcraft and small industry development in Ghana (Reports 000361), 1964; Hale, P. (Peter) (Box 21)
  The improvement of the making and marketing of handicraft through modern techniques is discussed.
  Office of the Vice President; Africa and the Middle East/West Africa
  Handicraft -- Ghana; Small business -- Ghana; Industries -- Ghana; Artisans -- Ghana
- A plan for the development of the Nigerian Institute of Management and Administration (Reports 000362), 1961; Hoslett, Schuyler Dean, 1918- (Box 21)
  A working plan for the set up of the institute and its operation is given.
  06190381;06190013
  Executives -- Training of -- Nigeria; Research institutes -- Nigeria; Business administration -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria; Executors and administrators -- Training of -- Nigeria; Nigerian Institute of Management
- Training scheme for the government construction and maintenance industries in Tanganyika (Reports 000363), 1963; Host, Mogens; Frederiksen, Ernst; Norrman, Christer (Box 21)
  There is a need within the government of Tanzania for a special training center to meet the engineering and building fields requirements for construction staff.
  06290261
  45 p.
  Manual training -- Tanzania; Construction industry -- Tanzania; Building trades -- Tanzania; Engineering -- Tanzania; Technical education -- Tanzania; Tanzania. Ministry of Communications, Labour, and Works
- Memorandum concerning applied research in Nigeria (Reports 000364), 1963; Host, Mogens; Topsøe, Haldor, 1913- (Box 21)
  Applied research is discussed in general. Recommendations are made for the establishment of a National Research Council of Nigeria to be set up as an industrial body to advise on activities of research in Nigeria.
  L62-1042
  Applied research in Nigeria
  Industries -- Nigeria; Research -- Nigeria; Federal Institute of Industrial Research, Oshodi
- English language teaching in the Syrian Arab Republic: Observations and recommendations (Reports 000365), 1963; Jacobs, Robert (Box 21)
  Africa and the Middle East/Middle East and North Africa
  06300032
  Syrian Arab Republic
  Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Syria; Education, Bilingual -- Syria; Language teachers -- Syria; Teachers -- Training of -- Syria
- Development of legal education in Ghana (Reports 000366), 1963; Harvey, William Burnett (Box 21)
  126 p.
  Legal education in Ghana
  Law -- Study and teaching -- Ghana; Law schools -- Ghana; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.)
- Progress report on: Accelerated Rice Research Program of East Pakistan: (Reports 000367), 1966; Alim, Abdul, 1919-; Hasan-uz-Zaman, S. M. (Syed Muhammad); Johnson, L. P. V. (Box 21)
  Accelerated Rice Research Program of East Pakistan
  Agricultural research projects -- Bangladesh; Rice -- Research -- Bangladesh; Agriculture -- Bangladesh -- Economic aspects; International Rice Research Institute
- Kenya Meeting of Representatives: dealing with "hard" political cases (Reports 000368), 1968; Heaps, David (Box 21)
  Agenda paper for Session VII, Emerging issues for the Foundation.
  4 leaves -- 28 cm.
  International relations
- Report on a study of the University of Calcutta (Reports 000369), 1963; Berdie, Ralph F. (Ralph Freimuth), 1916-; Middlebrook, William T.; Wantman, Morey J. (Box 21)
  All aspects of the university are studied.
  06190249
  149 p.
  Curriculum evaluation -- India; School facilities -- India; Universities and colleges -- India -- Administration; University of Calcutta
- Report on the steel production programming in India to the Ministry of Steel, Mines, and Heavy Engineering (Reports 000370), 1964; Byrne, Robert F. (Box 21)
  This report presents a multiple objective planning system for steel production in the Indian economy.
  Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  05900021
  Administrative Staff College Of India
  Steel production programming in India
  Steel industry and trade -- India; Production planning -- India; Administrative Staff College of India
- Manpower and employment in India (Reports 000371), 1965; Clark, Robert L. (Box 21)
  Manpower is defined. Governmental agencies having to do with manpower utilization are evaluated and suggestions are given for improving the employment situation in India.
  06200262
  The Institute Of Applied Manpower Research
  Personnel management -- India; Employment (Economic theory) -- India; Institute of Applied Manpower Research (India)
- Proposal for establishment of a National Development Corps: outline of a programme to develop physical resources of the Nation and provide productive experience and training for Indian youth (Reports 000372), 1964; Clark, Robert L.; McEwen, Bruce G. (Box 21, Reel R-9301)
  The proposed corps would be a nationwide development-oriented body of young men recruited on a voluntary basis. The participants operating in work camps of 300-500 corpsmen each, would carry out broad spectrum of productive and essential services.
  Youth -- Employment -- India; Human capital -- India; Personnel management -- India; National Resources Development Corps.
- Notes taken on a trip around the world to study fertilizer production, marketing, and efficient use: September 15-October 22 (Reports 000373), 1965; Donahue, Roy Luther, 1908- (Box 21)
  Agricultural industries -- Worldwide; Fertilizers -- Worldwide; Agriculture -- Worldwide
- The Jakarta Faculty of Economics final version (Reports 000374), 1965; Dye, Richard W. (Box 21)
  Ford Foundation role in developing the economics department at the University of Indonesia is analyzed. Study of technical assistance as it relates to institution-building in underdeveloped countries.
  06500356
  Midwest Universities Consortium For International Activities, Inc.
  86 p. -- 28 cm.
  Education, Higher -- Indonesia -- Endowments; Economics -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- Indonesia
- Report on trip to India, January 17--February 4 (Reports 000375), 1964; Eastman, Nicholson J. (Nicholson Joseph), 1895-1973 (Box 21, Reel R-9301)
  An all out effort should be made to elicit the interest and participation of the leading obstetricians and gynecologists of India in population control.
  Birth control -- India; Sterilization -- India
- Notes on Indonesia and Burma (Reports 000376), 1961; Quinn, John A. (Box 21)
  Ford Foundation program to date is discussed. The vast majority of grants are in the field of education.
  Educational development -- Indonesia; Educational development -- Burma; Rural development -- Indonesia; Rural development -- Burma; Vocational education -- Indonesia; Vocational education -- Burma; Education, Higher -- Indonesia; Education, Higher -- Burma
- Defense and development planning in India (Reports 000377), 1963; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 22, Reel R-9301)
  In the face of invasion by the Republic of China, India's defense will actually require the acceleration of agricultural and industrial development rather than the opposite.
  Defense systems -- India; Military planning -- India; Rural development -- India; Industrialization -- India; Personnel management -- India; Strategic intelligence -- India
- Frontiers of change (Reports 000378), 1963; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 22)
  Dag Hammarskjold Memorial Lecture given at the School of International Affairs, Columbia University New York, May 6, 1963. As a result of the scientific and technical revolution, the world has grown smaller, the world's food potential has multiplied and t
  Social change -- Asia; International relations
- Urbanism: a growing world problem (Reports 000379), 1963; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 22)